edublogs.org 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy -Edublogs – education blogs for teachers, students and schools

Please find our [Terms of Service here](http://edublogs.org/terms-of-service/).

**Your privacy is critically important to us. At Edublogs we have a few fundamental principles:**

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We too don’t like services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * In our blogging products, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals.

If you have questions about accessing or correcting your personal data please contact our [ **support team**](http://edublogs.org/contact/).

It is Edublogs’ policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Edublogs and our parent company, Incsub, collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Edublogs’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Edublogs’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Edublogs may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Edublogs also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on Edublogs.org blogs. Edublogs only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Edublogs’s websites choose to interact with Edublogs in ways that require Edublogs to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Edublogs gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at Edublogs.org to provide a username and in some cases, an email address. Those who engage in transactions with Edublogs – by upgrading to a Pro account, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Edublogs collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Edublogs. Edublogs does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Edublogs may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Edublogs may monitor the most popular blogs on the Edublogs site or use spam screened by our filters to help identify spam. Edublogs may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Edublogs does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

Edublogs uses Google Analytics for stat tracking including Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. These stats are never shared, sold, or used for purposes other than to understand our visitors and improve our service.

Using Ads Settings, visitors can [opt-out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Edublogs discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Edublogs’s behalf or to provide services available at Edublogs’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Edublogs’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Edublogs will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Edublogs discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Edublogs believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Edublogs, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Edublogs website and have supplied your email address, Edublogs may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Edublogs and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Edublogs takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework**  
Edublogs and our parent company, Incsub, LLC complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Incsub, LLC has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Incsub, LLC’s certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Incsub commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Incsub at:

support@edublogs.org

Incsub,LLC  
11900 Jollyville Rd. #202546  
Austin, TX 78720  
USA

Incsub has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Incsub, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Edublogs uses cookies to help Edublogs identify and track visitors, their usage of Edublogs website, and their website access preferences. Edublogs visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Edublogs’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Edublogs’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Ads**

The Edublogs platform is 100% advertising free.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Edublogs may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Edublogs’s sole discretion. Edublogs encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
